27. Wild Tasmania. Where can you find wombats, eagles, devils, and 10,000-year-old trees?
It's an island that goes by many names. Van Diemen's Land, Durvan, and Tassie. Have you
guessed Tasmania yet? If you haven't, don't feel bad. Tasmania's still pretty unknown,
even though it's the 26th biggest island in the world. Tasmania sits below Australia.
It looks like a miniature Australia, turned upside down. It is a state of the country
of Australia, but it is separated from the rest of the country by the Bass Strait. Can
it really be so far from the real world that devils live there? Well, the Tasmanian devil
does. The Tasmanian devil is a marsupial, an animal with a pouch like a kangaroo. It
looks a little bit like a very small bear. It's called a devil because it has a frightening
growl that scared early Tasmanians. These animals also tend to be very mean, which makes the
name Tasmanian devil even more appropriate. Tasmania is home to lots of unusual animals.
There are wombats, which look like furry little pigs and live in burrows underground.
There are wallabies, which look just like little kangaroos. And then there are birds
and frogs of all shapes and sizes, and strange little mammals that lay eggs.
Tasmania also has amazing flora or plant life. It has huge temperate rainforests and huge
eucalyptus forests. Some Tasmanian eucalyptus trees are some of the tallest in the world,
more than 300 feet tall and still growing. Tasmania also has a tree called the Huron
Pine that lives to be very, very old. There are Huron Pines in Tasmania from 2,000 to
10,000 years old. Tasmania is truly unlike anywhere else.